JOE: People with Autism may have
difficulties with interpreting
verbal information and processing
it and in turn have problems
communicating verbally themselves.
It often helps if the person
verbally communicating is
precise and sticks to the point.
An autistic person finds it difficult
to filter out the irrelevancies
within a conversation which can
create an overland of information.
Also other stimuli such as different
sounds can also be distracting making it
hard to focus on the verbal information.
Sometimes the lack of speech
comprehension is interpreted by others
as an unwillingness to answer or engage
with, when in fact the person simply
isn’t able to retrieve the meaning at
that moment and needs time to respond.
Let’s hear more about this…